A Guide to the Rebecca C. Lancefield papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA173
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence
  - Smith, Thomas B., 1971 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Snyder, Richard L., 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Speert, David P., 1979 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Stein, William H., 1972 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Stetson, Chandler A., 1952 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Swift, Homer F., 1942 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Tillotson, James R., 1977 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Updyke, Elaine L., 1952 1972 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Van Slyke, Donald, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Wald, Ellen R., 1977 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Wannamaker, Lewis W. and Hallie, 1969 1971 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Watson, Robert F., 1955 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Wiley, Grove G., 1967-1968 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Wilkinson, Hazel, 1974 1977 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Williams, R.E.O., 1955-1965 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Wilson, Armine, 1943 circa 1940s 1952 1963 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Wilson, Graham S., 1951 1964 1969 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Woolcock, Dr., 1968 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Woollam, D.H.M., 1962 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Addition to collection, 1986 January 3; (5" Letter)
  - Correspondence files
    - Hare, R. Correspondence and lab notes, circa 1933-1936 (Box 10, Folder 1-2)
      [Includes some correspondence with L. Colebrook, circa 1935-1936].
    - Wiley, Grove G. re Wiley/Wilson ms, 1960 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Wilson, Armine T., 1942 1953 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence re types, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript files
    - Robert Watson. Autopsy paper, circa 1959 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - T. Duckett Jones Memorial Award Lecture, 1960 October 8 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - T. Duckett-Jones Memorial Lecture, 1965 October 15 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Griffith Lecture, 1968 April 1 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Armine T. Wilson Lecture, 1968 May 3 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - re Workshop/Carol J. Baker, circa 1976 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Tai, Gotschlich, and Rebecca C. Lancefield. Type Ib Paper, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Undated I (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - "Biological studies of hemolytic streptococci with special reference to medical aspects" Group lecture, early
      - "Unsolved problems of the non-suppurative complications of Group A streptococcal infections" Ann G. Kuttner and Rebecca C. Lancefield
      - Rebecca C. Lancefield holograph attached to scientific photos, re ms. for J. Hygiene Griffith Memorial volume
    - Undated II (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Abstracts of 2 lectures
      - Unidentified, incomplete draft; pages missing
      - "Immuno and chemical studies of variation in streptococci"
  - Laboratory notes, circa 1940-1950 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Includes Sharpies runs; mouse passage; M extract
  - Tables re antigenic composition (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Rebecca C. Lancefield's notes on The Chemistry and Biology of Sialic Acid... by Alfred Gottschalk (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Rebecca C. Lancefield reprints (miscellaneous) (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Reprints by others: P. Levine article on K. Landsteiner; photocopy of P. Rous biog. memoir on Landsteiner with annotations (by Levine?), with Levine note (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Laboratory Notebooks
  - A-B, 1934-1957
    - Absorption-Steward, 1942-1944 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Active Immunity with M. 1937-1938, Sharpies Plcrate Method # 7 to # 40 1934-1939, 1937-1938 1934-1939 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Bactericidal Tests-Mouse Protection with Human Serum, Book 1, 1954-1955; 1 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Bactericidal Tests-Mouse Protection with Human Serum, Book 1, 1954-1955; 2 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Book 2, 1955-1956; 1 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Book 2, 1955-1956; 2 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Book 3, 1956-1957; 1 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Book 3, 1956-1957; 2 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - B, 1958-1968
    - Bactericidal Tests, Book 4, 1957-1958; 1 of 2 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Book 4, 1957-1958; 2 of 2 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Type 22. S. 43 Col. Antigens, Book 5, 1958-1959; 1 of 2 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Type 22, S. 43 Col. Antigens, Book 5, 1958-1959; 2 of 2 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Type 50, Summary, Book 6, 1960-1964 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Type 50, Summary, Book 6, 1960-1964 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Miscellaneous 181, Col. Picks A. A-avar Group A Type S 23 Bur A [undeciphered]... Book 6a, 1966-1967 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Notes on Material Sent out, Book 7, 1967-1968; 1 of 2 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Notes on Material Sent out, Book 7, 1967-1968; 2 of 2 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - B, 1954-1971
    - Bactericidal Tests, T2 & C649A, Book 8, 1968-1970; 1 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Bactericidal Tests, T2 & C649A, Book 8, 1968-1970; 2 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Double Differsion Stock Sera, Odds & Ends, Group A CDC Standard Strains, Book 9, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Double Differsion Stock Sera, Odds & Ends, Group A CDC Standard Strains, Book 9, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Type 12, Book 10, 1969-1970 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Human Index, 1954-1958; 1 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Human Index, 1954-1958; 2 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Bactericidal Tests, Rabbit Index, 1954-1958 1967-1969; 1 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - B-C, 1928-1969
    - Bactericidal Tests, Rabbit Index, 1954-1958 1967-1969; 2 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Bovine Strips, Early Grouping Preps? 090 G-B, 1932-1933 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Bovine Strips, Early Grouping Preps? 090 G-B, 1932-1933 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - C203, Type 1 and 3, 1936-1939 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Coburn Groups, Summer, 1933-1935 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Current Notes, 1928-1931; 1 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Current Notes, 1928-1931; 2 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - C-G, 1939-1976
    - Current, 1973-1976 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Digest Series, Boiled Series, Chicken Experiments Groups, 1941-1944; 1 of 2 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Digest Series, Boiled Series, Chicken Experiments Groups, 1941-1944; 2 of 2 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Digest T, 1942-1945; 1 of 2 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Digest T, 1942-1945; 2 of 2 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - General Method-Includes Egg Work, Media Records, Formamide C, Salicylade dtn., AFL Streptolysin Production, Mailed Cultures and Sera, Antistreptolysin O-Globulin Preparation, 1939-1966; 1 of 2 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - General Method-Includes Egg Work, Media Recods, Formamide C, Salicylade dtn., AFL Streptolysin Production, Mailed Cultures and Sera, Antistreptolysin O-Globulin Preparation, 1939-1966; 2 of 2 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - G, 1962-1974
    - Group B, la & lb. Also Cultures Sent in, Bactericidal Group B, 1961 SDE Proteinases and Zymogen? 1965 Book I, 1962-1964, 1961-1965; 1 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Group B, la & lb. Also Cultures Sent in, Bactericidal Group B, 1961 SDE Proteinases and Zymogen? 1965 Book I, 1962-1964, 1961-1965; 2 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Group B, Cho., List of Sera Culture Sent in, Book II, 1965; 1 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Group B, Cho., List of Sera Culture Sent in, Book II, 1965; 2 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Group B, Cho., Also Culture Sent in, Book III, 1964-1967; 1 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Group B, Cho., Also Culture Sent in, Book III, 1964-1967; 2 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Group B, Cultures Trans. to Book I, Sialic Acid Book IV, 1964-1970 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Group B, [undeciphered small label], 1966 1970-1974; 1 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Group B, [undeciphered small label], 1966 1970-1974; 1 of 2 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - G, 1932-1976
    - Group B Types, Exp. # 33-41, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Group B, Records (started (12/18/1974), 1 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Group B, Records (started (12/18/1974), 2 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Group D, 1975-1976 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Group Sera, Mostly Early Grouping, Identification of Strains, 1933-1941; 1 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Group Sera, Mostly Early Grouping, Identification of Strains, 1933-1941; 2 of 2 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Group Serum Titrations and Absorptions, 1934-1952 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - G, 1934-1946
    - Grouping & Typing, 1934-1935, Griffith Type Culture and Sera, Received May 1935 Correspondence Fry? & Y.M.C. Haloes? Book I, 1934-1938; 1 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Grouping & Typing, 1934-1935, Griffith Type Culture and Sera, Received May 1935 Correspondence Fry? & Y.M.C. Haloes? Book I, 1934-1938; 2 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Grouping & Typing, Book II, 1937-1938 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Grouping & Typing, Sharpies Runs, Book III, 1937-1946; 1 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Grouping & Typing, Sharpies Runs, Book 111, 1937-1946; 2 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Grouping & Typing, Book IV, 1942-1943; 1 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Grouping & Typing, Book IV, 1942-1943; 2 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - G[rouping] & T[yping], Book V, 1942-1943; 1 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - G[rouping] & T[yping], Book V, 1942-1943; 2 of 2 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - G-L, 1935-1963
    - Grouping & Typing, Book VI, 1944-1955; 1 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Grouping & Typing, Book VI, 1944-1955; 2 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Haverstraw Cultures, 1942 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Immunized Rabbits, Completed Sets, 1935-1940; 1 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Immunized Rabbits, Completed Sets, 1935-1940; 2 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Loring Airforce Base, 1962-1963; 1 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Loring Airforce Base, 1962-1963; 2 of 2 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - M-P, 1943-1962
    - Miscellaneous Type 50, B154 & F156, Protection Test Group C, and Protoplast Reversion, Multiple Col Picks F156, 1960-1962; 1 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous Type 50, B154 & F156, Protection Test Group C, and Protoplast Reversion, Multiple Col Picks F156, 1960-1962; 2 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Monkey Experiment con't (sic), 1943-1945 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Mouse Epidemic, 1960-1961; 1 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Mouse Epidemic, 1960-1961; 2 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Mouse Epizootics, Summaries, 1960-1961; 1 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Mouse Epizootics, Summaries, 1960-1961; 2 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Pasients, Bacteriostatic Antibodies, 1943-1944; 1 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Pasients, Bacteriostatic Antibodies, 1943-1944; 2 of 2 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - P-R, 1933-1966
    - Purification Tim. Cellulose, Column. AM13-15, Mickle, 1949-1953; 1 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Purification Tim. Cellulose, Column. AM13-15, Mickle, 1949-1953; 2 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Rabbit Book (Early), 1933-1938; 1 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Rabbit Book (Early), 1933-1938; 2 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Rabbit Book, 1943-1945 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Rabbit Immunization Ia, 1939-1941 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Rabbit Record, Type 1-46, 1941-1944; 1 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Rabbit Record, Type 1-46, 1941-1944; 2 of 2 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Rockland Farms, Breeding Mice, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - R, 1940-1948
    - RS Series, 1940-1947; 1 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - RS Series, 1940-1947; 2 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - RS & RSC Series Precipitins, 1942-1944; 1 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - RS & RSC Series Precipitins, 1942-1944; 2 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - R.S. Group Antistreptolysin Titrations, 1940-1942; 1 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - R.S. Group Antistreptolysin Titrations, 1940-1942; 2 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - RS Series Serum Tests, Preserved Culture, 1942-1948; 1 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - RS Series Serum Tests, Preserved Culture, 1942-1948; 2 of 2 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - S, 1942-1974
    - Serum Analyses, Protection Ia-Ib-Ic, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Serum Sent out, D-Z, 1943-1946; 1 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Serum Sent out, D-Z, 1943-1946; 2 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Slide Agglutinations, Analysis of Related Types, 1941-1942; 1 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Slide Agglutinations, Analysis of Related Types, 1941-1942; 2 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Steward, Walter A. Streps Heated 100 C. Antisera, 1943-1944; 1 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Steward, Walter A. Streps Heated 100 C. Antisera, 1943-1944; 2 of 2 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Survey Group A to find Variants C. Polysac?, 1953-1953 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - T, 1931-1948
    - T Extracts & Agglut. Heated Cultures Agglut. C-G Relations, Types 17-23 & Compact, 1934-1940; 1 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - T Extracts & Agglut. Heated Cultures Agglut. C-G Relations, Types 17-23 & Compact, 1934-1940; 2 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - TM (AM1-13), 1945-1950. Early Prep. M Antigens D,? Sharples Tests, 1946-1947 and Testing of M?, 1946-1947, Prep. NH & ALT?, 1 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - TM (AM1-13), 1945-1950. Early Prep. M Antigens D,? Sharples Tests, 1946-1947 and Testing of M?, 1946-1947, Prep. NH & ALT?, 2 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - T28 M Prep., Prep T28 R (called M), 1948; 1 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - T28 M Prep., Prep T28 R (called M), 1948; 2 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Test Bleeding S & C of Group B, Miscellaneous Group B, 1931-1933; 1 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Test Bleeding S & C of Group B, Miscellaneous Group B, 1931-1933; 2 of 2 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - T-V, 1933-1952
    - 28 M & R, 1950; 1 of 2 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - 28 M & R, 1950; 2 of 2 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - 28 etc. Adjuvant C510 M1-3, C649A, M1-M2, 28 R in Other Group, Prep 28 DH. 28 ME III, T Extract Pakula Slide Agg, 1951-1952; 1 of 2 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - 28 etc. Adjuvant C510 M1-3, C649A, M1-M2, 28 R in other Group, Prep 28 DH. 28 ME III, T Extract Pakula Slide Agg, 1951-1952; 2 of 2 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Typing, Test Bleeding, G.P. Streps, 1933-1934 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Variant C, 1951-1953; 1 of 2 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Variant C., 1951-1953; 2 of 2 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - U, 1925-1974
    - [illegible label] Apparently Protection Test, Data, 1972-1974; 1 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - [illegible label] Apparently Protection Test, Data, 1972-1974; 2 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Untitled RS RSC Data, 1942-1945 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Untitled, 1925-1928; 1 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Untitled, 1925-1928; 2 of 2 (Box 27, Folder 5)
- Appendix I: Manuscripts on technical procedures in the Rebecca C. Lancefield Papers, File on "Typing charts, methods, and procedures" (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - "Technical procedures employed in the production and use of streptococcus grouping sera". The Hospital of The Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research, 1955 May; I
    - Photocopy 1, 1a; clean, but title page missing, 5 pp.
    - Photocopy 2: title page, with Rebecca C. Lancefield revisions in pencil and pen, including slip of paper for insert, 1b; 7 pp.
  - "Method of drying streptococcus cultures in current use at the Rockefeller Hospital", 1959 September 18; II; Photocopy, 2 pp.
  - "Method for preparing typing antisera for Group A streptococci", 1960 May; III; Photocopy, 2 pp.
  - "Method of drying streptococcus cultures in current use at the Rockefeller Hospital", 1967 March 7; IV; Photocopy, 2 pp.
  - Undated: "Todd-Hewitt Broth", V; Carbon typescript, 2 pp. 450 L221 Box 3, Folder 2